

Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

© (+84) 168 4643 181 | ■ nguyentrucxinh@outlook.com | 🏕 nguyentrucxinh.github.io | 🖸 nguyentrucxinh | 🗖 nguyentrucxinh

"Built tools to help human solve problems."

## **Summary**

JavaScript junkie and Java lover. Current Java Developer at outsourcing company Sutrix Group. 2+ years experience specializing in both backend and frontend development. Interested in learning new technologies and tools if the need arises. Favorite stacks: Node.js/React/MongoDB - JavaEE/Spring/Hibernate. Mostly.

## Education

#### **HUTECH (Ho Chi Minh University of Technology)**

Ho Chi Minh, Vietnam

Oct. 2012 - Oct. 2016

**BIT - BACHELOR OF INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY** 

• Got a Chun Shin-Il Scholarship which is given to promising students in CSE Dept.

# Work Experience \_\_\_\_\_

**Sutrix Group** Ho Chi Minh, Vietnam

JAVA WEB DEVELOPER

Aug. 2017 - PRESENT

- Built several automated environments to provision and manage a hybrid infrastructure(Amazon AWS + On-premise) utilizing IaC(Infrastructure as Code) tools like Ansible, Packer and Terraform.
- Designed an overall service architecture and pipelines of the Machine Learning based Fashion Tagging API SaaS product with the micro-services architecture.
- Implemented several API microservices in Node.js Koa and in the serverless AWS Lambda functions.

#### Software Company Tin Tan. Co., Ltd.

Ho Chi Minh, Vietnam

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER

Mar. 2016 - Jul. 2017

- Implemented RESTful API server for car rental booking application (CARPLAT in Google Play).
- Built and deployed overall service infrastructure utilizing Docker container, CircleCl, and several AWS stack(Including EC2, ECS, Route 53, S3, CloudFront, RDS, ElastiCache, IAM), focusing on high-availability, fault tolerance, and auto-scaling.
- Developed an easy-to-use Payment module which connects to major PG(Payment Gateway) companies in Korea.

## **Projects**

## TechBridge Market (Developers' Network of POSTECH)

Pohang, S.Korea

CORE MEMBER & PRESIDENT AT 2013

Jun. 2010 - Jun. 2017

- Reformed the society focusing on software engineering and building network on and off campus.
- Proposed various marketing and network activities to raise awareness.

#### Transport Management & Vending Machine Management

Pohang, S.Korea

MEMBER

Sep. 2010 - Oct. 2011

- Gained expertise in hacking & security areas, especially about internal of operating system based on UNIX and several exploit techniques.
- Participated on several hacking competition and won a good award.
- · Conducted periodic security checks on overall IT system as a member of POSTECH CERT.
- Conducted penetration testing commissioned by national agency and corporation.

## Clinic Management (Laboratory for UNIX Security in POSTECH)

Pohang, S.Korea

MEMBER

Sep. 2010 - Oct. 2011

- · Gained expertise in hacking & security areas, especially about internal of operating system based on UNIX and several exploit techniques.
- Participated on several hacking competition and won a good award.
- Conducted periodic security checks on overall IT system as a member of POSTECH CERT.
- Conducted penetration testing commissioned by national agency and corporation.

# Skills

Languages Vietnamese (Native), English

#### **Technical skills**

- JavaScript ES5 & ES6 (1y5m)
- Node.js/Express.js
- MongoDB/Mongoose
- React/Redux
- Angular/TypeScript (1y5m)
- Microservices (1y)
- Java SE/EE (1y)
- Spring/Hibernate (1y)
- PHP/Laravel (1y5m)
- JIRA (1y)
- Coding Convertions

- Web services: REST/SOAP (2y)
- Authentication: JWT/OAuth2 (2y)
- PaaS: Google Cloud Platform, Heroku (1y)
- Version control: Git (2y)
- DBMS: MySQL, MSSQL (2y)
- HTML/CSS/jQuery/Bootstrap/Pug
- Principles: SOLID, DRY, KISS, YAGNI
- Design Patterns
- Object-Oriented Programming
- Functional Programming
- Reactive Programming